# Federico Castellano

9 de Julio 6 E, Córdoba - Argentina

https://www.linkedin.com/in/federico-castellano

fedec15@gmail.com | (+54) (9) 3515726714

#### Profile

• Expertise in Cognitive Science, Data Science, and Computer Science

#### Skills

Languages Python (+2 years), Java (+1 year), SQL (+1 year), HTML-CSS (1 year)

Tools Jupyter, pandas, matplotlib, seaborn, numpy, scipy, scikit-learn, tensorflow, flask, git

Data Science Statistics, data analysis, optimization, machine learning, neural networks

## Experience

2019-present Data Scientist at MercadoLibre

I am in charge of developing and maintaining an entire integrated system (a rest API) for delivering shipping-time promises at MercadoLibre, based on machine learning/statistics models. I work diary with Python, SQL, Tableau, Git, and many other tools to develop data

analyses, metrics, models, dashboards, and so on.

2018–2019 Postdoctoral Researcher

Consejo Nacional de Investigaciones Científicas y Técnicas (CONICET) – Argentina

I worked on the hypothesis that cognitive maps and other spatial mental representations are computationally structured in ways that allow them to be processed pretty much like

linguistic representations, making them computationally suitable for inferences.

2016–2017 Visiting Researcher

Department of Philosophy and Cognitive Science, Rutgers University, New Jersey – USA I worked on different theories of concepts from a computational point of view, concluding that concepts understood as feature vector representations and as rules of inference are

the best choices for accounting for different cognitive tasks.

2013–2018 Doctoral Researcher

Consejo Nacional de Investigaciones Científicas y Técnicas (CONICET) – Argentina I critically analyzed the explanatory power of different models of perception (naïve,

computational, and connectionist) to account for conceptual classification.

### Personal Projects

2019-Present Predictive model for house prices in Cordoba City

Based on a dataset got from webscrapping, which includes more than 30.000 properties from Córdoba City (Argentina), I developed a model for predicting house prices. To do so, I

made use of Python, Beautiful Soap, Pandas, SkiLearn, Matplotlib and Flask.

http://maerion.pythonanywhere.com/ | https://github.com/fedec15

2018–2019 Publications in Towards Data Science (Medium)

https://medium.com/@federicocastellano

Development of 'Sistema de gestión de alumnos UPC' (in Java)

I developed a free desktop application for Faculty at the *Universidad Provincial de Córdoba*.

This project was entirely developed in Java.

https://github.com/fedec15

Education

2013–2018 PhD in Philosophy (with focus in Cognitive Science)

Universidad Nacional de Córdoba, Argentina

2007–2013 B.A. in Philosophy

Universidad Nacional de Córdoba, Argentina

Courses

2020-Present Statistics with Python Specialization

University of Michigan - Coursera

2018–2019 Foundations of Machine Learning

Bloomberg ML EDU | https://bloomberg.github.io/foml/#about

2018–2019 Software Engineer Specialization

*Universidad Tecnológica Nacional (UTN) – Regional Buenos Aires* 

2018–2019 Artificial Neural Networks

Prof. F. Tamarit. FAMAF, Universidad Nacional de Córdoba (UNC)

Idioms

Spanish Native

English Professional Proficiency

Portuguese Basic